[
  {
    "i": 1,
    "problem": "1.\\ \\left(\\left(\\cfrac{\\sqrt{a}+\\sqrt{b}}{\\sqrt[4]{a}-\\sqrt[4]{b}}\\right)^{-1}-\n\\cfrac{2\\sqrt[4]{ab}}{b^{\\frac{3}{4}}-a^{\\frac{1}{4}}b^{\\frac{1}{2}}+\na^{\\frac{1}{2}}b^{\\frac{1}{4}}-a^{\\frac{3}{4}}}\\right)^{-1},\\\\\n",
    "solution": "1. $\\left(\\left(\\cfrac{\\sqrt{a}+\\sqrt{b}}{\\sqrt[4]{a}-\\sqrt[4]{b}}\\right)^{-1}-\n\\cfrac{2\\sqrt[4]{ab}}{b^{\\frac{3}{4}}-a^{\\frac{1}{4}}b^{\\frac{1}{2}}+\na^{\\frac{1}{2}}b^{\\frac{1}{4}}-a^{\\frac{3}{4}}}\\right)^{-1}=[x=\\sqrt[4]{a},\\ y=\\sqrt[4]{b}]=$\\\\$\n\\left(\\cfrac{x-y}{x^2+y^2}-\\cfrac{2xy}{y^3-xy^2+x^2y-x^3}\\right)^{-1}=\n\\left(\\cfrac{x-y}{x^2+y^2}-\\cfrac{2xy}{y^2(y-x)+x^2(y-x)}\\right)^{-1}=$\\\\$\n\\left(\\cfrac{x-y}{x^2+y^2}-\\cfrac{2xy}{(y-x)(x^2+y^2)}\\right)^{-1}=\n\\left(\\cfrac{x-y}{x^2+y^2}+\\cfrac{2xy}{(x-y)(x^2+y^2)}\\right)^{-1}=\n\\left(\\cfrac{x^2-2xy+y^2+2xy}{(x-y)(x^2+y^2)}\\right)^{-1}=$\\\\$x-y=\\sqrt[4]{a}-\\sqrt[4]{b}.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 2,
    "problem": "2.\\ a^{\\frac{4}{3}}\\cdot\\left(\\cfrac{3}{\\sqrt[3]{a^2}-\\sqrt[3]{a}+1}-\n\\cfrac{3}{a+1}+\\cfrac{\\sqrt[3]{a}-1}{\\sqrt[3]{a^2}-1}\\right)^{-1}\n\\left(\\cfrac{a^{-\\frac{1}{3}}+1}{a^\\frac{1}{3}}\\right)^2,\\\\\n\\end{array}$\\\\\n$\\begin{array}{ll}\n",
    "solution": "2. $a^{\\frac{4}{3}}\\cdot\\left(\\cfrac{3}{\\sqrt[3]{a^2}-\\sqrt[3]{a}+1}-\n\\cfrac{3}{a+1}+\\cfrac{\\sqrt[3]{a}-1}{\\sqrt[3]{a^2}-1}\\right)^{-1}\n\\left(\\cfrac{a^{-\\frac{1}{3}}+1}{a^\\frac{1}{3}}\\right)^2=[x=\\sqrt[3]{a}]=$\\\\$\nx^4\\cdot\\left(\\cfrac{3}{x^2-x+1}-\\cfrac{3}{x^3+1}+\\cfrac{x-1}{x^2-1}\\right)^{-1}\\left(\\cfrac{\\cfrac{1}{x}+1}{x}\\right)^2=$\\\\$\nx^4\\cdot\\left(\\cfrac{3}{x^2-x+1}-\\cfrac{3}{(x+1)(x^2-x+1)}+\\cfrac{1}{x+1}\\right)^{-1}\\left(\\cfrac{x+1}{x^2}\\right)^2=$\\\\$\nx^4\\cdot\\left(\\cfrac{3x+3-3+x^2-x+1}{(x+1)(x^2-x+1)}\\right)^{-1}\\cfrac{(x+1)^2}{x^4}=\n\\left(\\cfrac{(x+1)^2}{(x+1)(x^2-x+1)}\\right)^{-1}(x+1)^2=\\cfrac{x^3+1}{(x+1)^2}(x+1)^2=x^3+1=a+1.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 3,
    "problem": "3.\\ \\left(\\cfrac{n-m}{\\sqrt{n}+\\sqrt{m}}\\right)^2:\\left(\\cfrac{\\sqrt{n^3}-\\sqrt{m^3}}{\\sqrt{n}-\\sqrt{m}}-\n3\\sqrt{mn}\\right),&\n",
    "solution": "3. $\\left(\\cfrac{n-m}{\\sqrt{n}+\\sqrt{m}}\\right)^2:\\left(\\cfrac{\\sqrt{n^3}-\\sqrt{m^3}}{\\sqrt{n}-\\sqrt{m}}-3\\sqrt{mn}\\right)=\n[x=\\sqrt{n},\\ y=\\sqrt{m}]=\\left(\\cfrac{x^2-y^2}{x+y}\\right)^2:\\left(\\cfrac{x^3-y^3}{x-y}-3xy\\right)=\n\\left(x-y\\right)^2:\\left(x^2+xy+y^2-3xy\\right)=(x-y)^2:(x-y)^2=1.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 4,
    "problem": "4.\\ \\left(\\cfrac{\\sqrt{a^3}-\\sqrt{b^3}}{\\sqrt{a}-\\sqrt{b}}+\n\\sqrt{ab}\\right)\\left(\\cfrac{\\sqrt{a}-\\sqrt{b}}{a-b}\\right)^2,\\\\\n",
    "solution": "4. $\\left(\\cfrac{\\sqrt{a^3}-\\sqrt{b^3}}{\\sqrt{a}-\\sqrt{b}}+\\sqrt{ab}\\right)\\left(\\cfrac{\\sqrt{a}-\\sqrt{b}}{a-b}\\right)^2=[x=\\sqrt{a},\\ y=\\sqrt{b}]=\n\\left(\\cfrac{x^3-y^3}{x-y}+xy\\right)\\left(\\cfrac{x-y}{x^2-y^2}\\right)^2=(x^2+xy+y^2+xy)\\left(\\cfrac{1}{x+y}\\right)^2=\n(x+y)^2\\cfrac{1}{(x+y)^2}=1.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 5,
    "problem": "5.\\ \\left(\\cfrac{\\sqrt[4]{ab^3}-\\sqrt[4]{a^3b}}{\\sqrt{a}-\\sqrt{b}}\\right)^{-2}\\cdot\n\\sqrt{1+\\cfrac{a}{b}+2\\sqrt{\\cfrac{a}{b}}},&\n",
    "solution": "5. $\\left(\\cfrac{\\sqrt[4]{ab^3}-\\sqrt[4]{a^3b}}{\\sqrt{a}-\\sqrt{b}}\\right)^{-2}\\cdot\\sqrt{1+\\cfrac{a}{b}+2\\sqrt{\\cfrac{a}{b}}}=[x=\\sqrt[4]{a},\\ y=\\sqrt[4]{b}]=\n\\left(\\cfrac{xy^3-x^3y}{x^2-y^2}\\right)^{-2}\\cdot\\sqrt{1+\\cfrac{x^4}{y^4}+2\\cfrac{x^2}{y^2}}=\n\\left(\\cfrac{-xy(x^2-y^2)}{x^2-y^2}\\right)^{-2}\\cdot\\sqrt{\\left(1+\\cfrac{x^2}{y^2}\\right)^2}=\n\\cfrac{1}{x^2y^2}\\cdot\\cfrac{x^2+y^2}{y^2}=\\cfrac{x^2+y^2}{x^2y^4}=\\cfrac{\\sqrt{a}+\\sqrt{b}}{b\\sqrt{a}}.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 6,
    "problem": "6.\\ \\left((\\sqrt[4]{a}-\\sqrt[4]{b})^{-1}+(\\sqrt[4]{a}+\\sqrt[4]{b})^{-1}\\right)^{-2}:\n\\cfrac{a-b}{4(\\sqrt{a}+\\sqrt{b})},\\\\\n",
    "solution": "6. $\\left((\\sqrt[4]{a}-\\sqrt[4]{b})^{-1}+(\\sqrt[4]{a}+\\sqrt[4]{b})^{-1}\\right)^{-2}:\\cfrac{a-b}{4(\\sqrt{a}+\\sqrt{b})}=[x=\\sqrt[4]{a},\\ y=\\sqrt[4]{b}]=\n\\left((x-y)^{-1}+(x+y)^{-1}\\right)^{-2}:\\cfrac{x^4-y^4}{4(x^2+y^2)}=\n\\left(\\cfrac{1}{x-y}+\\cfrac{1}{x+y}\\right)^{-2}\\cdot\\cfrac{4(x^2+y^2)}{(x^2-y^2)(x^2+y^2)}=\n\\left(\\cfrac{x+y+x-y}{(x-y)(x+y)}\\right)^{-2}\\cdot\\cfrac{4}{x^2-y^2}=\n\\cfrac{(x-y)^2(x+y)^2}{4x^2}\\cdot\\cfrac{4}{(x-y)(x+y)}=\\cfrac{x^2-y^2}{x^2}=\\cfrac{\\sqrt{a}-\\sqrt{b}}{\\sqrt{a}}.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 7,
    "problem": "7.\\ \\left(\\sqrt{y}-\\cfrac{x}{\\sqrt{y}}\\right):\\left(\\sqrt{\\cfrac{x}{y}}-\n\\sqrt{\\cfrac{y}{x}}\\right),&\n",
    "solution": "7. $\\left(\\sqrt{y}-\\cfrac{x}{\\sqrt{y}}\\right):\\left(\\sqrt{\\cfrac{x}{y}}-\\sqrt{\\cfrac{y}{x}}\\right)=[a=\\sqrt{x},\\ b=\\sqrt{y}]=\n\\left(b-\\cfrac{a^2}{b}\\right):\\left(\\cfrac{a}{b}-\\cfrac{b}{a}\\right)=\\cfrac{b^2-a^2}{b}:\\cfrac{a^2-b^2}{ab}=-a=-\\sqrt{x}.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 8,
    "problem": "8.\\ \\left(\\cfrac{y}{\\sqrt{x}}-\\sqrt{x}\\right):\\left(\\sqrt{\\cfrac{x}{y}}-\n\\sqrt{\\cfrac{y}{x}}\\right),\\\\\n",
    "solution": "8. $\\left(\\cfrac{y}{\\sqrt{x}}-\\sqrt{x}\\right):\\left(\\sqrt{\\cfrac{x}{y}}-\\sqrt{\\cfrac{y}{x}}\\right)=[a=\\sqrt{x},\\ b=\\sqrt{y}]=\n\\left(\\cfrac{b^2}{a}-a\\right):\\left(\\cfrac{a}{b}-\\cfrac{b}{a}\\right)=\n\\cfrac{b^2-a^2}{a}:\\cfrac{a^2-b^2}{ab}=-b=-\\sqrt{y}.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 9,
    "problem": "9.\\ \\cfrac{\\sqrt{a-2\\sqrt{a-1}}}{1-\\sqrt{a-1}}\\ (a>2),&\n",
    "solution": "9. $\\cfrac{\\sqrt{a-2\\sqrt{a-1}}}{1-\\sqrt{a-1}}=\\cfrac{\\sqrt{a-1-2\\sqrt{a-1}+1}}{1-\\sqrt{a-1}}=\\cfrac{\\sqrt{(\\sqrt{a-1}-1)^2}}{1-\\sqrt{a-1}}=\n\\cfrac{\\sqrt{a-1}-1}{1-\\sqrt{a-1}}=-1.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 10,
    "problem": "10.\\ \\cfrac{\\sqrt{a-2\\sqrt{a-1}}}{1-\\sqrt{a-1}}\\ (1\\leqslant a<2),\\end{array}$ \\\\\n$\\begin{array}{ll}\n",
    "solution": "10. $\\cfrac{\\sqrt{a-2\\sqrt{a-1}}}{1-\\sqrt{a-1}}=\\cfrac{\\sqrt{a-1-2\\sqrt{a-1}+1}}{1-\\sqrt{a-1}}\\cfrac{\\sqrt{(\\sqrt{a-1}-1)^2}}{1-\\sqrt{a-1}}=\n\\cfrac{1-\\sqrt{a-1}}{1-\\sqrt{a-1}}=1.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 11,
    "problem": "11.\\ \\cfrac{x-y}{\\sqrt{x}+\\sqrt{y}}:\\left(\\left(x^\\frac{1}{4}-y^\\frac{1}{4}\\right)^{-1}+\n\\left(x^\\frac{1}{4}+y^\\frac{1}{4}\\right)^{-1}\\right)^{-2},&\n",
    "solution": "11. $\\cfrac{x-y}{\\sqrt{x}+\\sqrt{y}}:\\left(\\left(x^\\frac{1}{4}-y^\\frac{1}{4}\\right)^{-1}+\\left(x^\\frac{1}{4}+y^\\frac{1}{4}\\right)^{-1}\\right)^{-2}=[a=x^{\\frac{1}{4}},\\ b=y^\\frac{1}{4}]=\\cfrac{a^4-b^4}{a^2+b^2}:\\left(\\cfrac{1}{a-b}+\\cfrac{1}{a+b}\\right)^{-2}=\n(a^2-b^2)\\cdot\\left(\\cfrac{a+b+a-b}{a^2-b^2}\\right)^{2}=(a^2-b^2)\\cfrac{4a^2}{(a^2-b^2)^2}=\\cfrac{4a^2}{a^2-b^2}=\\cfrac{4\\sqrt{x}}{\\sqrt{x}-\\sqrt{y}}.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 12,
    "problem": "12.\\ \\left(\\cfrac{1}{\\left(a^\\frac{1}{2}+b^\\frac{1}{2}\\right)^{-2}}-\\left(\\cfrac{\\sqrt{a}-\\sqrt{b}}{a^\\frac{3}{2}-b^\\frac{3}{2}}\\right)^{-1}\\right):\\sqrt{ab},\\end{array}$  \\\\\n$\\begin{array}{ll}\n",
    "solution": "12. $\\left(\\cfrac{1}{\\left(a^\\frac{1}{2}+b^\\frac{1}{2}\\right)^{-2}}-\\left(\\cfrac{\\sqrt{a}-\\sqrt{b}}{a^\\frac{3}{2}-b^\\frac{3}{2}}\\right)^{-1}\\right):\\sqrt{ab}=\n[a=x^{\\frac{1}{2}},\\ b=y^\\frac{1}{2}]=\\left(\\cfrac{1}{\\left(x+y\\right)^{-2}}-\\left(\\cfrac{x-y}{x^3-y^3}\\right)^{-1}\\right):(xy)=\n\\left(x^2+2xy+y^2-x^2-xy-y^2\\right):(xy)=1.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 13,
    "problem": "13.\\ (1-a^2):\\left(\\left(\\cfrac{1-a\\sqrt{a}}{1-\\sqrt{a}}+\\sqrt{a}\\right)\\cdot\n\\left(\\cfrac{1+a\\sqrt{a}}{1+\\sqrt{a}}-\\sqrt{a}\\right)\\right)+1,\n\\end{array}$ \\\\\n$\\begin{array}{ll}\n",
    "solution": "13. $(1-a^2):\\left(\\left(\\cfrac{1-a\\sqrt{a}}{1-\\sqrt{a}}+\\sqrt{a}\\right)\\cdot\\left(\\cfrac{1+a\\sqrt{a}}{1+\\sqrt{a}}-\\sqrt{a}\\right)\\right)+1=[x=\\sqrt{a}]=$\\\\$\n(1-x^4):\\left(\\left(\\cfrac{1-x^3}{1-x}+x\\right)\\cdot\\left(\\cfrac{1+x^3}{1+x}-x\\right)\\right)+1=\n(1-x^4):\\left(\\left(1+x+x^2+x\\right)\\cdot\\left(1-x+x^2-x\\right)\\right)+1=\n(1-x^4):\\left((1+x)^2\\cdot(1-x)^2\\right)+1=(1+x^2)(1-x^2):(1-x^2)^2+1=\\cfrac{1+x^2}{1-x^2}+1=\\cfrac{2}{1-x^2}=\\cfrac{2}{1-a}.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 14,
    "problem": "14.\\ \\cfrac{(\\sqrt{x}-\\sqrt{y})^3+\\cfrac{2x^2}{\\sqrt{x}}+y\\sqrt{y}}{x\\sqrt{x}+y\\sqrt{y}}+\n\\cfrac{3\\sqrt{xy}-3y}{x-y},&\n",
    "solution": "14. $\\cfrac{(\\sqrt{x}-\\sqrt{y})^3+\\cfrac{2x^2}{\\sqrt{x}}+y\\sqrt{y}}{x\\sqrt{x}+y\\sqrt{y}}+\\cfrac{3\\sqrt{xy}-3y}{x-y}=[a=\\sqrt{x},\\ b=\\sqrt{y}]=\n\\cfrac{(a-b)^3+\\cfrac{2a^4}{a}+b^3}{a^3+b^3}+\\cfrac{3ab-3b^2}{a^2-b^2}=\n\\cfrac{a^3-3a^2b+3ab^2-b^3+2a^3+b^3}{a^3+b^3}+\\cfrac{3b(a-b)}{(a-b)(a+b)}=\n\\cfrac{3a(a^2-ab+b^2)}{(a+b)(a^2-ab+b^2)}+\\cfrac{3b}{a+b}=\\cfrac{3a+3b}{a+b}=3.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 15,
    "problem": "15.\\ \\left(\\cfrac{27^\\frac{1}{2}-a^{-\\frac{3}{2}}}{3^\\frac{1}{2}-a^{-\\frac{1}{2}}}+3^{\\frac{1}{2}} a^{-\\frac{1}{2}}\n\\right):(3-a^{-1})-\\cfrac{2a^{-\\frac{1}{2}}}{3^\\frac{1}{2}-a^{-\\frac{1}{2}}},\\end{array}$\\\\$\\begin{array}{lll}\n",
    "solution": "15. $\\left(\\cfrac{27^\\frac{1}{2}-a^{-\\frac{3}{2}}}{3^\\frac{1}{2}-a^{-\\frac{1}{2}}}+3^{\\frac{1}{2}} a^{-\\frac{1}{2}}\n\\right):(3-a^{-1})-\\cfrac{2a^{-\\frac{1}{2}}}{3^\\frac{1}{2}-a^{-\\frac{1}{2}}}=[x=3^{\\frac{1}{2}},\\ y=a^{-\\frac{1}{2}}]=\n\\left(\\cfrac{x^3-y^3}{x-y}+xy\\right):(x^2-y^2)-\\cfrac{2y}{x-y}=\\cfrac{x^2+xy+y^2+xy}{(x-y)(x+y)}-\\cfrac{2y}{x-y}=\n\\cfrac{(x+y)^2}{(x-y)(x+y)}-\\cfrac{2y}{x-y}=\\cfrac{x+y-2y}{x-y}=1.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 16,
    "problem": "16.\\ \\left(\\cfrac{8^\\frac{1}{2}+y^{-\\frac{3}{2}}}{2^\\frac{1}{2}+y^{- \\frac{1}{2}}}-\n2^\\frac{1}{2}y^{-\\frac{1}{2}}\\right):(2-y^{-1})+\\cfrac{2y^{-\\frac{1}{2}}}{2^\\frac{1}{2}+y^{-\\frac{1}{2}}},\\\\\n",
    "solution": "16. $\\left(\\cfrac{8^\\frac{1}{2}+y^{-\\frac{3}{2}}}{2^\\frac{1}{2}+y^{- \\frac{1}{2}}}-\n2^\\frac{1}{2}y^{-\\frac{1}{2}}\\right):(2-y^{-1})+\\cfrac{2y^{-\\frac{1}{2}}}{2^\\frac{1}{2}+y^{-\\frac{1}{2}}}=[x=2^{\\frac{1}{2}},\\ z=y^{-\\frac{1}{2}}]=\n\\left(\\cfrac{x^3+z^3}{x+z}-xz\\right):(x^2-z^2)+\\cfrac{2z}{x+z}=\\cfrac{x^2-xz+z^2-xz}{(x-z)(x+z)}+\\cfrac{2z}{x+z}=\n\\cfrac{(x-z)^2}{(x-z)(x+z)}+\\cfrac{2z}{x+z}=\\cfrac{x-z+2z}{x+z}=1.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 17,
    "problem": "17.\\ \\left(\\cfrac{x-9}{x+3\\sqrt{x}+9}\\cdot\\left(\\cfrac{x^{0,5}+3}{x^{1,5}-27}\\right)^{-1}\\right)^{0,5}+x^{0,5}\\\n(0<x<9),\\end{array}$ \\\\ $\\begin{array}{ll}\n",
    "solution": "17. $\\left(\\cfrac{x-9}{x+3\\sqrt{x}+9}\\cdot\\left(\\cfrac{x^{0,5}+3}{x^{1,5}-27}\\right)^{-1}\\right)^{0,5}+x^{0,5}=[a=\\sqrt{x}]=\n\\left(\\cfrac{a^2-9}{a^2+3a+9}\\cdot\\left(\\cfrac{a+3}{a^3-27}\\right)^{-1}\\right)^{0,5}+a=\n\\left(\\cfrac{(a-3)(a+3)}{a^2+3a+9}\\cdot\\cfrac{(a-3)(a^2+3a+9)}{a+3}\\right)^{0,5}+a=((a-3)^2)^{0,5}+a=3-a+a=3.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 18,
    "problem": "18.\\ \\left(\\cfrac{a^\\frac{3}{2}-8}{a^\\frac{1}{2}+2}\\cdot\\left(\\cfrac{a+2\\sqrt{a}+4}{a-4}\\right)^{-1}\\right)^\\frac{1}{2}-a^\\frac{1}{2}\\\n(a>4),&\n",
    "solution": "18. $\\left(\\cfrac{a^\\frac{3}{2}-8}{a^\\frac{1}{2}+2}\\cdot\\left(\\cfrac{a+2\\sqrt{a}+4}{a-4}\\right)^{-1}\\right)^\\frac{1}{2}-a^\\frac{1}{2}=[x=a^\\frac{1}{2}]=\n\\left(\\cfrac{x^3-8}{x+2}\\cdot\\left(\\cfrac{x^2+2x+4}{x^2-4}\\right)^{-1}\\right)^\\frac{1}{2}-x=$\\\\$\n\\left(\\cfrac{(x-2)(x^2+2x+4)}{x+2}\\cdot\\cfrac{(x-2)(x+2)}{x^2+2x+4}\\right)^\\frac{1}{2}-x=((x-2)^2)^\\frac{1}{2}-x=x-2-x=-2.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 19,
    "problem": "19.\\ \\left(\\cfrac{\\sqrt{a}-2}{a+2\\sqrt{a}}+\\cfrac{\\sqrt{a}+2}{a-2\\sqrt{a}}\\right)\\cdot\n\\cfrac{a^\\frac{3}{2}}{a+4}-\\cfrac{8}{a-4},\\\\\n",
    "solution": "19. $\\left(\\cfrac{\\sqrt{a}-2}{a+2\\sqrt{a}}+\\cfrac{\\sqrt{a}+2}{a-2\\sqrt{a}}\\right)\\cdot\n\\cfrac{a^\\frac{3}{2}}{a+4}-\\cfrac{8}{a-4}=[x=\\sqrt{a}]=\n\\left(\\cfrac{x-2}{x^2+2x}+\\cfrac{x+2}{x^2-2x}\\right)\\cdot\\cfrac{x^3}{x^2+4}-\\cfrac{8}{x^2-4}=\n\\left(\\cfrac{x-2}{x(x+2)}+\\cfrac{x+2}{x(x-2)}\\right)\\cdot\\cfrac{x^3}{x^2+4}-\\cfrac{8}{x^2-4}=\n\\cfrac{x^2-4x+4+x^2+4x+4}{x(x+2)(x-2)}\\cdot\\cfrac{x^3}{x^2+4}-\\cfrac{8}{x^2-4}=\n\\cfrac{2(x^2+4)}{x(x+2)(x-2)}\\cdot\\cfrac{x^3}{x^2+4}-\\cfrac{8}{x^2-4}=\n\\cfrac{2x^2}{(x+2)(x-2)}-\\cfrac{8}{(x+2)(x-2)}=\\cfrac{2x^2-8}{(x+2)(x-2)}=\\cfrac{2(x-2)(x+2)}{(x+2)(x-2)}=2.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 20,
    "problem": "20.\\ \\left(\\cfrac{\\sqrt{x-1}}{\\sqrt{x-1}+\\sqrt{x+1}}+\\cfrac{x-1}{\\sqrt{x^2-1}-x+1}\\right)\n(x^2-1)^{-\\frac{1}{2}},\\end{array}$\\\\$\\begin{array}{ll}\n",
    "solution": "20. $\\left(\\cfrac{\\sqrt{x-1}}{\\sqrt{x-1}+\\sqrt{x+1}}+\\cfrac{x-1}{\\sqrt{x^2-1}-x+1}\\right)(x^2-1)^{-\\frac{1}{2}}=[a=\\sqrt{x-1},\\ b=\\sqrt{x+1}]=$\\\\$\n\\left(\\cfrac{a}{a+b}+\\cfrac{a^2}{ab-a^2}\\right)((ab)^2)^{-\\frac{1}{2}}=\\left(\\cfrac{a}{a+b}+\\cfrac{a^2}{a(b-a)}\\right):(ab)=\n\\cfrac{ba-a^2+a^2+ab}{b^2-a^2}:(ab)=\\cfrac{2}{b^2-a^2}=$\\\\$\\cfrac{2}{x+1-x+1}=1.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 21,
    "problem": "21.\\ \\left(\\cfrac{a^2+4}{a^3+2\\sqrt{2}}-\\cfrac{1}{a+\\sqrt{2}}\\right):\n\\left(\\cfrac{a^2}{\\sqrt{2}}-a+\\sqrt{2}\\right)^{-1},\\\\\n",
    "solution": "21. $\\left(\\cfrac{a^2+4}{a^3+2\\sqrt{2}}-\\cfrac{1}{a+\\sqrt{2}}\\right):\\left(\\cfrac{a^2}{\\sqrt{2}}-a+\\sqrt{2}\\right)^{-1}=[b=\\sqrt{2}]=\n\\left(\\cfrac{a^2+2b^2}{a^3+b^3}-\\cfrac{1}{a+b}\\right):\\left(\\cfrac{a^2}{b}-a+b\\right)^{-1}=\n\\left(\\cfrac{a^2+2b^2}{(a+b)(a^2-ab+b^2)}-\\cfrac{1}{a+b}\\right):\\left(\\cfrac{a^2-ab+b^2}{b}\\right)^{-1}=\n\\cfrac{a^2+2b^2-a^2+ab-b^2}{(a+b)(a^2-ab+b^2)}\\cdot\\cfrac{a^2-ab+b^2}{b}=$\\\\$\\cfrac{b(a+b)}{(a+b)b}=1.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 22,
    "problem": "22.\\ \\left(\\cfrac{a^\\frac{3}{2}+1}{a-1}-\\cfrac{a}{\\sqrt{a}+1}-\\cfrac{1}{\\sqrt{a}-1}\\right)\n\\cdot\\left(\\cfrac{1}{1+a^{-\\frac{1}{2}}}\\right)^{-1},\\end{array}$\\\\ $\\begin{array}{ll}\n",
    "solution": "22. $\\left(\\cfrac{a^\\frac{3}{2}+1}{a-1}-\\cfrac{a}{\\sqrt{a}+1}-\\cfrac{1}{\\sqrt{a}-1}\\right)\\cdot\\left(\\cfrac{1}{1+a^{-\\frac{1}{2}}}\\right)^{-1}=[x=a^\\frac{1}{2}]=\n\\left(\\cfrac{x^3+1}{x^2-1}-\\cfrac{x^2}{x+1}-\\cfrac{1}{x-1}\\right)\\cdot\\left(\\cfrac{1}{1+\\cfrac{1}{x}}\\right)^{-1}$\\\\$=\n\\cfrac{x^3+1-x^3+x^2-x-1}{(x-1)(x+1)}\\cdot\\left(\\cfrac{x}{x+1}\\right)^{-1}=\n\\cfrac{x(x-1)}{(x-1)(x+1)}\\cdot\\cfrac{x+1}{x}=1.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 23,
    "problem": "23.\\ \\left(\\cfrac{\\sqrt{x}-\\sqrt{y}}{x\\sqrt{y}+\\sqrt{x}y}+\\cfrac{\\sqrt{x}+\\sqrt{y}}{x\\sqrt{y}-\\sqrt{x}y}\\right)\n\\cdot\\cfrac{\\sqrt{x^3}\\sqrt{y}}{x+y},&\n",
    "solution": "23. $\\left(\\cfrac{\\sqrt{x}-\\sqrt{y}}{x\\sqrt{y}+\\sqrt{x}y}+\\cfrac{\\sqrt{x}+\\sqrt{y}}{x\\sqrt{y}-\\sqrt{x}y}\\right)\n\\cdot\\cfrac{\\sqrt{x^3}\\sqrt{y}}{x+y}=[a=\\sqrt{x},\\ b=\\sqrt{y}]=\n\\left(\\cfrac{a-b}{a^2b+ab^2}+\\cfrac{a+b}{a^2b-ab^2}\\right)\\cdot\\cfrac{a^3b}{a^2+b^2}=\n\\left(\\cfrac{a-b}{ab(a+b)}+\\cfrac{a+b}{ab(a-b)}\\right)\\cdot\\cfrac{a^3b}{a^2+b^2}=\n\\cfrac{a^2-2ab+b^2+a^2+2ab+b^2}{ab(a-b)(a+b)}\\cdot\\cfrac{a^3b}{a^2+b^2}=\n\\cfrac{2(a^2+b^2)}{ab(a-b)(a+b)}\\cdot\\cfrac{a^3b}{a^2+b^2}=\\cfrac{2a^2}{a^2-b^2}=\\cfrac{2x}{x-y}.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 24,
    "problem": "24.\\ \\cfrac{m-n}{\\sqrt{m}(\\sqrt[4]{m}-\\sqrt[4]{n})}-\\cfrac{\\sqrt{m}-\\sqrt{n}}{\\sqrt[4]{m}-\\sqrt[4]{n}},\\\\\n",
    "solution": "24. $\\cfrac{m-n}{\\sqrt{m}(\\sqrt[4]{m}-\\sqrt[4]{n})}-\\cfrac{\\sqrt{m}-\\sqrt{n}}{\\sqrt[4]{m}-\\sqrt[4]{n}}=[x=\\sqrt[4]{m},\\ y=\\sqrt[4]{n}]=\n\\cfrac{x^4-y^4}{x^2(x-y)}-\\cfrac{x^2-y^2}{x-y}=\\cfrac{x^4-y^4}{x^2(x-y)}-\\cfrac{x^2-y^2}{x-y}=\\cfrac{x^4-y^4-x^4+x^2y^2}{x^2(x-y)}=\n\\cfrac{y^2(x-y)(x+y)}{x^2(x-y)}=\\cfrac{y^2(x+y)}{x^2}=(\\sqrt[4]{m}+\\sqrt[4]{n})\\sqrt{\\cfrac{n}{m}}.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 25,
    "problem": "25.\\ \\left(\\cfrac{x\\sqrt{x}-8}{x-3\\sqrt{x}+2}-\\cfrac{6\\sqrt{x}}{\\sqrt{x}-1}\\right):\n\\left(1-\\cfrac{1}{\\sqrt{x}-1}\\right),&\n",
    "solution": "25. $\\left(\\cfrac{x\\sqrt{x}-8}{x-3\\sqrt{x}+2}-\\cfrac{6\\sqrt{x}}{\\sqrt{x}-1}\\right):\n\\left(1-\\cfrac{1}{\\sqrt{x}-1}\\right)=[a=\\sqrt{x}]=\n\\left(\\cfrac{a^3-8}{a^2-3a+2}-\\cfrac{6a}{a-1}\\right):\\left(1-\\cfrac{1}{a-1}\\right)=\n\\left(\\cfrac{(a-2)(a^2+2a+4)}{(a-2)(a-1)}-\\cfrac{6a}{a-1}\\right):\\left(\\cfrac{a-2}{a-1}\\right)=\n\\cfrac{a^2+2a+4-6a}{a-1}\\cdot\\cfrac{a-1}{a-2}=\\cfrac{(a-2)^2}{a-1}\\cdot\\cfrac{a-1}{a-2}=a-2=\\sqrt{x}-2.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 26,
    "problem": "26.\\ \\left(\\cfrac{x\\sqrt{x}+1}{x-\\sqrt{x}-2}+\\cfrac{3\\sqrt{x}}{\\sqrt{x}-2}\\right):\n\\left(\\cfrac{1}{3}+\\cfrac{1}{\\sqrt{x}-2}\\right),\n\\end{array}$\\\\$\\begin{array}{ll}\n",
    "solution": "26. $\\left(\\cfrac{x\\sqrt{x}+1}{x-\\sqrt{x}-2}+\\cfrac{3\\sqrt{x}}{\\sqrt{x}-2}\\right):\n\\left(\\cfrac{1}{3}+\\cfrac{1}{\\sqrt{x}-2}\\right)=[a=\\sqrt{x}]=\n\\left(\\cfrac{a^3+1}{a^2-a-2}+\\cfrac{3a}{a-2}\\right):\\left(\\cfrac{1}{3}+\\cfrac{1}{a-2}\\right)=\n\\left(\\cfrac{(a+1)(a^2-a+1)}{(a+1)(a-2)}+\\cfrac{3a}{a-2}\\right):\\left(\\cfrac{a-2+3}{3(a-2)}\\right)=\n\\cfrac{a^2-a+1+3a}{a-2}\\cdot\\cfrac{3(a-2)}{a+1}=\\cfrac{(a+1)^2}{a-2}\\cdot\\cfrac{3(a-2)}{a+1}=3a+3=3(\\sqrt{x}+1).$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 27,
    "problem": "27.\\ \\left(\\cfrac{\\sqrt{x^3}+\\sqrt{y^3}}{x-\\sqrt{x}\\sqrt{y}+y}+\n2xy\\cfrac{(\\sqrt{x})^{-1}-(\\sqrt{y})^{-1}}{x-y}\\right)(\\sqrt{x}+\\sqrt{y}),\\\\\n",
    "solution": "27. $\\left(\\cfrac{\\sqrt{x^3}+\\sqrt{y^3}}{x-\\sqrt{x}\\sqrt{y}+y}+\n2xy\\cfrac{(\\sqrt{x})^{-1}-(\\sqrt{y})^{-1}}{x-y}\\right)(\\sqrt{x}+\\sqrt{y})=[a=\\sqrt{x},\\ b=\\sqrt{y}]=$\\\\$\n\\left(\\cfrac{a^3+b^3}{a^2-ab+b^2}+2a^2b^2\\cfrac{\\cfrac{1}{a}-\\cfrac{1}{b}}{a^2-b^2}\\right)(a+b)=\n\\left(a+b+2a^2b^2\\cfrac{b-a}{ba(a-b)(a+b)}\\right)(a+b)=\\left(a+b-\\cfrac{2ab}{a+b}\\right)(a+b)=\n\\cfrac{a^2+2ab+b^2-2ab}{a+b}\\cdot(a+b)=a^2+b^2=x+y.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 28,
    "problem": "28.\\ \\left(\\cfrac{\\sqrt{a^3}-\\sqrt{b^3}}{a+\\sqrt{a}\\sqrt{b}+b}+\n2ab\\cfrac{(\\sqrt{a})^{-1}+(\\sqrt{b})^{-1}}{a-b}\\right)(\\sqrt{a}-\\sqrt{b}),\n\\end{array}$\\\\$\\begin{array}{ll}\n",
    "solution": "28. $\\left(\\cfrac{\\sqrt{a^3}-\\sqrt{b^3}}{a+\\sqrt{a}\\sqrt{b}+b}+\n2ab\\cfrac{(\\sqrt{a})^{-1}+(\\sqrt{b})^{-1}}{a-b}\\right)(\\sqrt{a}-\\sqrt{b})=[x=\\sqrt{a},\\ y=\\sqrt{b}]=$\\\\$\n\\left(\\cfrac{x^3-y^3}{x^2+xy+y^2}+2x^2y^2\\cfrac{\\cfrac{1}{x}+\\cfrac{1}{y}}{x^2-y^2}\\right)(x-y)=\n\\left(x-y+2x^2y^2\\cfrac{x+y}{xy(x-y)(x+y)}\\right)(x-y)=$\\\\$\\left(x-y+\\cfrac{2xy}{x-y}\\right)(x-y)=\n\\cfrac{x^2-2xy+y^2+2xy}{x-y}\\cdot(x-y)=x^2+y^2=a+b.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 29,
    "problem": "29.\\ \\cfrac{3\\cdot\\sqrt{x^2y}-x\\sqrt{25y}}{\\sqrt{64x^4y^3}},\\ (x<0),&\n",
    "solution": "29. $\\cfrac{3\\cdot\\sqrt{x^2y}-x\\sqrt{25y}}{\\sqrt{64x^4y^3}}=\\cfrac{-3x\\sqrt{y}-5x\\sqrt{y}}{8x^2y\\sqrt{y}}=\\cfrac{-8x\\sqrt{y}}{8x^2y\\sqrt{y}}=-\\cfrac{1}{xy}.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 30,
    "problem": "30.\\ \\cfrac{4\\cdot\\sqrt{x^2y}+x\\sqrt{9y}}{\\sqrt{x^4y^3}},\\ (x<0),\\\\\n",
    "solution": "30. $\\cfrac{4\\cdot\\sqrt{x^2y}+x\\sqrt{9y}}{\\sqrt{x^4y^3}}=\\cfrac{-4x\\sqrt{y}+3x\\sqrt{y}}{x^2y\\sqrt{y}}=\\cfrac{-x\\sqrt{y}}{x^2y\\sqrt{y}}=-\\cfrac{1}{xy}.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 31,
    "problem": "31.\\ \\cfrac{a^2+8a+15}{\\sqrt{a^2+10a+25}}+\\cfrac{a^2+3a+2}{\\sqrt{a^2+2a+1}}\\ (-5<a<-1),\\\\\n",
    "solution": "31. $\\cfrac{a^2+8a+15}{\\sqrt{a^2+10a+25}}+\\cfrac{a^2+3a+2}{\\sqrt{a^2+2a+1}}=\\cfrac{(a+3)(a+5)}{\\sqrt{(a+5)^2}}+\\cfrac{(a+2)(a+1)}{\\sqrt{(a+1)^2}}=\n\\cfrac{(a+3)(a+5)}{a+5}+\\cfrac{(a+2)(a+1)}{-(a+1)}=a+3-a-2=1.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 32,
    "problem": "32.\\ \\cfrac{a^2+9a+20}{\\sqrt{a^2+8a+16}}+\\cfrac{a^2+8a+12}{\\sqrt{a^2+4a+4}}\\ (-4<a<-2),\\\\\n",
    "solution": "32. $\\cfrac{a^2+9a+20}{\\sqrt{a^2+8a+16}}+\\cfrac{a^2+8a+12}{\\sqrt{a^2+4a+4}}=\\cfrac{(a+4)(a+5)}{\\sqrt{(a+4)^2}}+\\cfrac{(a+6)(a+2)}{\\sqrt{(a+2)^2}}=\n\\cfrac{(a+4)(a+5)}{a+4}+\\cfrac{(a+6)(a+2)}{-(a+2)}=a+5-a-6=-1.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 33,
    "problem": "33.\\ \\left(\\cfrac{1}{(a^\\frac{1}{2}+b^\\frac{1}{2})^{-2}}-\\cfrac{a^\\frac{3}{2}+\nb^\\frac{3}{2}}{a^\\frac{1}{2}+\nb^\\frac{1}{2}}\\right)^2\\cdot\\left(\\cfrac{27a^{-3}}{64b^{-6}}\\right)^{-\\frac{1}{3}},&\n",
    "solution": "33. $\\left(\\cfrac{1}{(a^\\frac{1}{2}+b^\\frac{1}{2})^{-2}}-\\cfrac{a^\\frac{3}{2}+\nb^\\frac{3}{2}}{a^\\frac{1}{2}+\nb^\\frac{1}{2}}\\right)^2\\cdot\\left(\\cfrac{27a^{-3}}{64b^{-6}}\\right)^{-\\frac{1}{3}}=[x=a^\\frac{1}{2},\\ y=b^\\frac{1}{2}]=\n\\left(\\cfrac{1}{(x+y)^{-2}}-\\cfrac{x^3+y^3}{x+y}\\right)^2\\cdot\\cfrac{3a}{4b^2}=$\\\\$\n\\left(x^2+2xy+y^2-x^2+xy-y^2\\right)^2\\cdot\\cfrac{4a}{3b^2}=\n9x^2y^2\\cdot\\cfrac{4a}{3b^2}=9ab\\cfrac{4a}{3b^2}=\\cfrac{12a^2}{b}.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 34,
    "problem": "34.\\ \\left(\\cfrac{d^3-8}{d^2-4}-\\cfrac{6d}{d+2}\\right):\\left(1-\\cfrac{4}{d+2}\\right)^2,\\\\\n",
    "solution": "34. $\\left(\\cfrac{d^3-8}{d^2-4}-\\cfrac{6d}{d+2}\\right):\\left(1-\\cfrac{4}{d+2}\\right)^2=\n\\left(\\cfrac{(d-2)(d^2+2d+4)}{(d-2)(d+2)}-\\cfrac{6d}{d+2}\\right):\\left(\\cfrac{d+2-4}{d+2}\\right)^2=$\\\\$\n\\cfrac{d^2+2d+4-6d}{d+2}\\cdot\\cfrac{(d+2)^2}{(d-2)^2}=\\cfrac{(d-2)^2}{d+2}\\cdot\\cfrac{(d+2)^2}{(d-2)^2}=d+2.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 35,
    "problem": "35.\\ \\cfrac{x+40}{x^3-16x}:\\left(\\cfrac{x-4}{3x^2+11x-4}-\\cfrac{16}{16-x^2}\\right),\n\\end{array}$\\\\\n$\\begin{array}{ll}\n",
    "solution": "35. $\\cfrac{x+40}{x^3-16x}:\\left(\\cfrac{x-4}{3x^2+11x-4}-\\cfrac{16}{16-x^2}\\right)=\n\\cfrac{x+40}{x(x-4)(x+4)}:\\left(\\cfrac{x-4}{(3x-1)(x+4)}+\\cfrac{16}{(x-4)(x+4)}\\right)=\n\\cfrac{x+40}{x(x-4)(x+4)}:\\cfrac{x^2-8x+16+48x-16}{(3x-1)(x-4)(x+4)}=\n\\cfrac{x+40}{x(x-4)(x+4)}\\cdot\\cfrac{(3x-1)(x-4)(x+4)}{x(x+40)}=\\cfrac{3x-1}{x^2}.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 36,
    "problem": "36.\\ \\left(\\left(x^\\frac{5}{6}-\\sqrt[3]{x}\\right):\\left(\\left(\n\\cfrac{x^\\frac{3}{4}-1}{x^\\frac{1}{4}-1}-x^\\frac{1}{2}\\right)\\cdot\n\\left(\n\\cfrac{x^\\frac{3}{4}+1}{x^\\frac{1}{4}+1}-x^\\frac{1}{2}\\right)\\right)\\right)^{-3},\\\\\n",
    "solution": "36. $\\left(\\left(x^\\frac{5}{6}-\\sqrt[3]{x}\\right):\\left(\\left(\n\\cfrac{x^\\frac{3}{4}-1}{x^\\frac{1}{4}-1}-x^\\frac{1}{2}\\right)\\cdot\n\\left(\n\\cfrac{x^\\frac{3}{4}+1}{x^\\frac{1}{4}+1}-x^\\frac{1}{2}\\right)\\right)\\right)^{-3}=[a=x^\\frac{1}{12}]=$\\\\$\n\\left(\\left(a^{10}-a^4\\right):\\left(\\left(\\cfrac{a^9-1}{a^3-1}-a^6\\right)\\cdot\\left(\\cfrac{a^9+1}{a^3+1}-a^6\\right)\\right)\\right)^{-3}=$\\\\$\n\\left(a^4(a^6-1):\\left(\\left(a^6+a^3+1-a^6\\right)\\cdot\\left(a^6-a^3+1-a^6\\right)\\right)\\right)^{-3}=\n\\left(a^4(a^6-1):\\left(\\left(a^3+1\\right)\\cdot\\left(1-a^3\\right)\\right)\\right)^{-3}=$\\\\$\n\\left(a^4(a^6-1):\\left(1-a^6\\right)\\right)^{-3}=(-a^4)^{-3}=-\\cfrac{1}{a^{12}}=-\\cfrac{1}{x}.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 37,
    "problem": "37.\\ \\cfrac{(x^2-y^2)(\\sqrt[3]{x}+\\sqrt[3]{y})}{\\sqrt[3]{x^5}+\\sqrt[3]{x^2y^3}-\n\\sqrt[3]{x^3y^2}-\\sqrt[3]{y^5}}-\\cfrac{x\\sqrt[3]{y}+\\sqrt[3]{y^4}}{(\\sqrt[3]{x}-\n\\sqrt[3]{y})^2+\\sqrt[3]{xy}},\n\\end{array}$\\\\\n$\\begin{array}{ll}\n",
    "solution": "37. $\\cfrac{(x^2-y^2)(\\sqrt[3]{x}+\\sqrt[3]{y})}{\\sqrt[3]{x^5}+\\sqrt[3]{x^2y^3}-\n\\sqrt[3]{x^3y^2}-\\sqrt[3]{y^5}}-\\cfrac{x\\sqrt[3]{y}+\\sqrt[3]{y^4}}{(\\sqrt[3]{x}-\n\\sqrt[3]{y})^2+\\sqrt[3]{xy}}=[a=\\sqrt[3]{x},\\ b=\\sqrt[3]{y}]=\n\\cfrac{(a^6-b^6)(a+b)}{a^5+a^2b^3-a^3b^2-b^5}-\\cfrac{a^3b+b^4}{(a-b)^2+ab}=\n\\cfrac{(a^6-b^6)(a+b)}{a^2(a^3+b^3)-b^2(a^3+b^3)}-\\cfrac{b(a^3+b^3)}{a^2-2ab+b^2+ab}=\n\\cfrac{(a-b)(a^2+ab+b^2)(a^3+b^3)(a+b)}{(a^3+b^3)(a-b)(a+b)}-\\cfrac{b(a+b)(a^2-ab+b^2)}{a^2-ab+b^2}=\na^2+ab+b^2-ab-b^2=a^2=\\sqrt[3]{x^2}.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 38,
    "problem": "38.\\ \\cfrac{x^3+5x^2+3x-9}{x-1},&\n",
    "solution": "38. $\\cfrac{x^3+5x^2+3x-9}{x-1}=\\cfrac{x^3-1+5(x^2-1)+3(x-1)}{x-1}=$\\\\$\\cfrac{(x-1)(x^2+x+1)+5(x-1)(x+1)+3(x-1)}{x-1}=\n\\cfrac{(x-1)(x^2+x+1)+5(x-1)(x+1)+3(x-1)}{x-1}=$\\\\$\\cfrac{(x-1)(x^2+x+1+5x+5+3)}{x-1}=x^2+6x+9=(x+3)^2.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 39,
    "problem": "39.\\ \\cfrac{x^3-5x^2+3x+9}{x+1},\\\\\n",
    "solution": "39. $\\cfrac{x^3-5x^2+3x+9}{x+1}=\\cfrac{x^3+1-5(x^2-1)+3(x+1)}{x+1}=$\\\\$\\cfrac{(x+1)(x^2-x+1)-5(x+1)(x-1)+3(x+1)}{x+1}=\n\\cfrac{(x+1)(x^2-x+1-5x+5+3)}{x+1}=x^2-6x+9=(x-3)^2.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 40,
    "problem": "40.\\ \\left(\\sqrt{a}+\\cfrac{b}{\\sqrt{a}-\\sqrt{b}}\\right)\\left(1-\\cfrac{\\sqrt{b^3}}{a\\sqrt{a}+b\\sqrt{b}}\\right)\n(\\sqrt{a}+\\sqrt{b}),\\\\\n",
    "solution": "40. $\\left(\\sqrt{a}+\\cfrac{b}{\\sqrt{a}-\\sqrt{b}}\\right)\\left(1-\\cfrac{\\sqrt{b^3}}{a\\sqrt{a}+b\\sqrt{b}}\\right)\n(\\sqrt{a}+\\sqrt{b})=[x=\\sqrt{a},\\ y=\\sqrt{b}]=\\left(x+\\cfrac{y^2}{x-y}\\right)\\left(1-\\cfrac{x^3}{x^3+y^3}\\right)$\\\\$(x+y)=\n\\cfrac{x^2-xy+y^2}{x-y}\\cdot\\cfrac{x^3+y^3-x^3}{(x+y)(x^2-xy+y^2}(x+y)=\\cfrac{y^3}{x-y}=\\cfrac{a\\sqrt{a}}{\\sqrt{a}-\\sqrt{b}}.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 41,
    "problem": "41.\\ \\left(\\sqrt{a}+\\cfrac{b}{\\sqrt{a}+\\sqrt{b}}\\right)\\left(1+\\cfrac{\\sqrt{b^3}}{a\\sqrt{a}-b\\sqrt{b}}\\right)\n(\\sqrt{a}-\\sqrt{b}),\\end{array}$\\\\\n$\\begin{array}{ll}\n",
    "solution": "41. $\\left(\\sqrt{a}+\\cfrac{b}{\\sqrt{a}+\\sqrt{b}}\\right)\\left(1+\\cfrac{\\sqrt{b^3}}{a\\sqrt{a}-b\\sqrt{b}}\\right)\n(\\sqrt{a}-\\sqrt{b})=[x=\\sqrt{a},\\ y=\\sqrt{b}]=\\left(x+\\cfrac{y^2}{x+y}\\right)\\left(1+\\cfrac{y^3}{x^3-y^3}\\right)$\\\\$\n(x-y)=\\cfrac{x^2+xy+y^2}{x+y}\\cdot\\cfrac{x^3-y^3+y^3}{(x-y)(x^2+xy+y^2)}(x-y)=\\cfrac{x^3}{x+y}=\\cfrac{a\\sqrt{a}}{\\sqrt{a}+\\sqrt{b}}.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 42,
    "problem": "42.\\ \\left(\\cfrac{a\\sqrt{a}+b\\sqrt{b}}{\\sqrt{a}+\\sqrt{b}}-\\sqrt{ab}\\right):(a-b)+\\cfrac{2\\sqrt{b}}{\\sqrt{a}+\\sqrt{b}},&\n",
    "solution": "42. $\\left(\\cfrac{a\\sqrt{a}+b\\sqrt{b}}{\\sqrt{a}+\\sqrt{b}}-\\sqrt{ab}\\right):(a-b)+\\cfrac{2\\sqrt{b}}{\\sqrt{a}+\\sqrt{b}}=[x=\\sqrt{a},\\ y=\\sqrt{b}]=\n\\left(\\cfrac{x^3+y^3}{x+y}-xy\\right):(x^2-y^2)+\\cfrac{2y}{x+y}=\n\\left(x^2-xy+y^2-xy\\right):((x-y)(x+y))+\\cfrac{2y}{x+y}=(x-y)^2:((x-y)(x+y))+\\cfrac{2y}{x+y}=\\cfrac{x-y+2y}{x+y}=1.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 43,
    "problem": "43.\\ \\left(\\cfrac{2}{\\sqrt{a}-\\sqrt{b}}-\\cfrac{2\\sqrt{a}}{a\\sqrt{a}+b\\sqrt{b}}\\cdot\\cfrac{a-\\sqrt{ab}+b}{\\sqrt{a}-\\sqrt{b}}\\right):4\\sqrt{b},\\end{array}$\\\\\n$\\begin{array}{ll}\n",
    "solution": "43. $\\left(\\cfrac{2}{\\sqrt{a}-\\sqrt{b}}-\\cfrac{2\\sqrt{a}}{a\\sqrt{a}+b\\sqrt{b}}\\cdot\\cfrac{a-\\sqrt{ab}+b}{\\sqrt{a}-\\sqrt{b}}\\right):4\\sqrt{b}=[x=\\sqrt{a},\\ y=\\sqrt{b}]=$\\\\$\\left(\\cfrac{2}{x-y}-\\cfrac{2x}{x^3+y^3}\\cdot\\cfrac{x^2-xy+y^2}{x-y}\\right):4y=\n\\left(\\cfrac{2}{x-y}-\\cfrac{2x}{(x+y)(x^2-xy+y^2)}\\cdot\\cfrac{x^2-xy+y^2}{x-y}\\right):4y=$\\\\$\n\\left(\\cfrac{2}{x-y}-\\cfrac{2x}{(x+y)(x-y)}\\right):4y=\n\\cfrac{2x+2y-2x}{(x+y)(x-y)}:4y=\\cfrac{1}{2(x^2-y^2)}=\\cfrac{1}{2(a-b)}.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 44,
    "problem": "44.\\ \\cfrac{x-y}{\\sqrt{x}-\\sqrt{y}}:\\left(\\left(x^\\frac{1}{4}-y^\\frac{1}{4}\\right)^{-1}+\\left(x^\\frac{1}{4}+y^\\frac{1}{4}\\right)^{-1}\\right)^{-2},&\n",
    "solution": "44. $\\cfrac{x-y}{\\sqrt{x}-\\sqrt{y}}:\\left(\\left(x^\\frac{1}{4}-y^\\frac{1}{4}\\right)^{-1}+\\left(x^\\frac{1}{4}+y^\\frac{1}{4}\\right)^{-1}\\right)^{-2}=[a=x^{\\frac{1}{4}},\\ b=y^\\frac{1}{4}]=\\cfrac{a^4-b^4}{a^2-b^2}:\\left(\\cfrac{1}{a-b}+\\cfrac{1}{a+b}\\right)^{-2}=\n(a^2+b^2)\\cdot\\left(\\cfrac{a+b+a-b}{a^2-b^2}\\right)^{2}=(a^2+b^2)\\cfrac{4a^2}{(a^2-b^2)^2}=\\cfrac{4a^2(a^2+b^2)}{(a^2-b^2)^2}=\\cfrac{4\\sqrt{x}(\\sqrt{x}+\\sqrt{y})}{(\\sqrt{x}-\\sqrt{y})^2}.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 45,
    "problem": "45.\\ \\cfrac{a+8b}{a^\\frac{2}{3}-4b^\\frac{2}{3}}:\\cfrac{a^\\frac{2}{3}b^\\frac{1}{3}-2a^\\frac{1}{3}b^\\frac{2}{3}+4b}{a^\\frac{2}{3}-2b^\\frac{1}{3}a^\\frac{1}{3}},\\\\\n",
    "solution": "45. $\\cfrac{a+8b}{a^\\frac{2}{3}-4b^\\frac{2}{3}}:\\cfrac{a^\\frac{2}{3}b^\\frac{1}{3}-2a^\\frac{1}{3}b^\\frac{2}{3}+4b}{a^\\frac{2}{3}-2b^\\frac{1}{3}a^\\frac{1}{3}}=\n[x=a^\\frac{1}{3},\\ y=b^\\frac{b}{3}]=\\cfrac{x^3+8y^3}{x^2-4y^2}:\\cfrac{x^2y-2xy^2+4y^3}{x^2-2yx}=$\\\\$\n\\cfrac{(x+2y)(x^2-2xy+4y^2)}{(x-2y)(x+2y)}\\cdot\\cfrac{x(x-2y)}{y(x^2-2xy+4y^2)}=\\cfrac{x}{y}=\\left(\\cfrac{a}{b}\\right)^\\frac{1}{3}.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 46,
    "problem": "46.\\ \\left(\\cfrac{a^{\\frac{3}{2}}+b^{\\frac{3}{2}}}{a^{\\frac{1}{2}}+b^{\\frac{1}{2}}}-(a+b)\\right)\\cdot\\cfrac{b^{\\frac{1}{2}}-a^{\\frac{1}{2}}}{a^{\\frac{1}{2}}b^{\\frac{3}{2}}-b^{\\frac{1}{2}}a^{\\frac{3}{2}}},&\n",
    "solution": "46. $\\left(\\cfrac{a^{\\frac{3}{2}}+b^{\\frac{3}{2}}}{a^{\\frac{1}{2}}+b^{\\frac{1}{2}}}-(a+b)\\right)\\cdot\\cfrac{b^{\\frac{1}{2}}-a^{\\frac{1}{2}}}{a^{\\frac{1}{2}}b^{\\frac{3}{2}}-b^{\\frac{1}{2}}a^{\\frac{3}{2}}}=\n[x=a^{\\frac{1}{2}}, y=b^{\\frac{1}{2}}]=\n\\left(\\cfrac{x^3+y^3}{x+y}-(x^2+y^2)\\right)\\cdot\\cfrac{y-x}{xy^3-yx^3}=$\\\\$\\left(\\cfrac{(x+y)(x^2-xy+y^2)}{x+y}-x^2-y^2\\right)\\cdot\\cfrac{y-x}{xy(y-x)(y+x)}=\n\\left(x^2-xy+y^2-x^2-y^2\\right)\\cdot\\cfrac{1}{xy(y+x)}=$\\\\$-xy\\cdot\\cfrac{1}{xy(y+x)}=-\\cfrac{1}{x+y}=-\\cfrac{1}{a^{\\frac{1}{2}}+b^{\\frac{1}{2}}}=\\cfrac{\\sqrt{b}-\\sqrt{a}}{a-b}.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 47,
    "problem": "47.\\ \\left(\\cfrac{a^{\\frac{3}{2}}-b^{\\frac{3}{2}}}{a^{\\frac{1}{2}}-b^{\\frac{1}{2}}}-(a^{\\frac{1}{2}}b^{\\frac{1}{2}}+2b)\\right):\\cfrac{ab^{\\frac{1}{2}}-ba^{\\frac{1}{2}}}{a^{\\frac{1}{2}}b^{\\frac{1}{2}}},\\\\\n\\end{array}$\\\\\n",
    "solution": "47. $\\left(\\cfrac{a^{\\frac{3}{2}}-b^{\\frac{3}{2}}}{a^{\\frac{1}{2}}-b^{\\frac{1}{2}}}-(a^{\\frac{1}{2}}b^{\\frac{1}{2}}+2b)\\right):\\cfrac{ab^{\\frac{1}{2}}-ba^{\\frac{1}{2}}}{a^{\\frac{1}{2}}b^{\\frac{1}{2}}}=\n[x=a^{\\frac{1}{2}}, y=b^{\\frac{1}{2}}]=\n\\left(\\cfrac{x^3-y^3}{x-y}-(xy+2y^2)\\right):\\cfrac{x^2y-y^2x}{xy}=$\\\\$\\left(\\cfrac{(x-y)(x^2+xy+y^2)}{x-y}-xy-2y^2\\right)\\cdot\\cfrac{xy}{xy(x-y)}=\n(x^2+xy+y^2-xy-2y^2)\\cdot\\cfrac{1}{x-y}=(x-y)(x+y)\\cdot\\cfrac{1}{x-y}=x+y=\\sqrt{a}+\\sqrt{b}.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 48,
    "problem": "48. $x\\left(\\left(\\cfrac{x^6-8}{x^4+2x^2+4}\\right)^{-1}-(x^2+2)^{-1}\\right)+(4-x^4)^{-1}:x^{-5},$\\\\\n",
    "solution": "48.$x\\left(\\left(\\cfrac{x^6-8}{x^4+2x^2+4}\\right)^{-1}-(x^2+2)^{-1}\\right)+(4-x^4)^{-1}:x^{-5}=\nx\\left(\\left(\\cfrac{(x^2-2)(x^4+2x^2+4)}{x^4+2x^2+4}\\right)^{-1}-\\cfrac{1}{x^2+2}\\right)+\\cfrac{x^5}{(2-x^2)(2+x^2)}=\nx\\left(\\cfrac{1}{x^2-2}-\\cfrac{1}{x^2+2}\\right)-\\cfrac{x^5}{(x^2-2)(x^2+2)}=\nx\\cdot\\cfrac{x^2+2-x^2+2}{(x^2-2)(x^2+2)}-\\cfrac{x^5}{(x^2-2)(x^2+2)}=\\cfrac{4x-x^5}{(x^2-2)(x^2+2)}=\n\\cfrac{x(2-x^2)(2+x^2)}{(x^2-2)(x^2+2)}=-x.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 49,
    "problem": "49. $(x^2-3x)^{-1}-\\left(\\cfrac{x^7+27x}{x^4-3x^2+9}\\right)^{-1}-2x^3\\cdot(3x^4-27)^{-1}.$\\\\\n",
    "solution": "49. $(x^3-3x)^{-1}-\\left(\\cfrac{x^7+27x}{x^4-3x^2+9}\\right)^{-1}-2x^3\\cdot(3x^4-27)^{-1}=\n\\cfrac{1}{x(x^2-3)}-\\left(\\cfrac{x(x^2+3)(x^4-3x^2+9)}{x^4-3x^2+9}\\right)^{-1}-\\cfrac{2x^3}{3(x^2-3)(x^2+3)}=\n\\cfrac{1}{x(x^2-3)}-\\cfrac{1}{x(x^2+3)}-\\cfrac{2x^3}{3(x^2-3)(x^2+3)}=\n\\cfrac{x^2+3-x^2+3}{x(x^2-3)(x^2+3)}-\\cfrac{2x^3}{3(x^2-3)(x^2+3)}=\n\\cfrac{18-2x^4}{3x(x^2-3)(x^2+3)}=\\cfrac{2(3-x^2)(3+x^2)}{3x(x^2-3)(x^2+3)}=-\\cfrac{2}{3x}.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 50,
    "problem": "50. $4ab+\\cfrac{\\left(1+\\left(\\cfrac{a}{b}\\right)^{-3}\\right)a^3}{(\\sqrt{a}+\\sqrt{b})^2-2\\sqrt{ab}}-\n\\cfrac{\\left(\\cfrac{\\sqrt{a}+\\sqrt{b}}{2b\\sqrt{a}}\\right)^{-1}+\n\\left(\\cfrac{\\sqrt{a}+\\sqrt{b}}{2a\\sqrt{b}}\\right)^{-1}}{\\left(\\cfrac{a+\\sqrt{ab}}{2}\\right)^{-1}+\n\\left(\\cfrac{b+\\sqrt{ab}}{2}\\right)^{-1}},$\\\\\n$\\begin{array}{ll}\n",
    "solution": "50. $4ab+\\cfrac{\\left(1+\\left(\\cfrac{a}{b}\\right)^{-3}\\right)a^3}{(\\sqrt{a}+\\sqrt{b})^2-2\\sqrt{ab}}-\\cfrac{\\left(\\cfrac{\\sqrt{a}+\\sqrt{b}}{2b\\sqrt{a}}\\right)^{-1}+\n\\left(\\cfrac{\\sqrt{a}+\\sqrt{b}}{2a\\sqrt{b}}\\right)^{-1}}{\\left(\\cfrac{a+\\sqrt{ab}}{2}\\right)^{-1}+\\left(\\cfrac{b+\\sqrt{ab}}{2}\\right)^{-1}}=$\\\\$\n4ab+\\cfrac{\\left(1+\\cfrac{b^3}{a^3}\\right)a^3}{a+2\\sqrt{ab}+b-2\\sqrt{ab}}-\\cfrac{\\cfrac{2b\\sqrt{a}}{\\sqrt{a}+\\sqrt{b}}+\n\\cfrac{2a\\sqrt{b}}{\\sqrt{a}+\\sqrt{b}}}{\\cfrac{2}{a+\\sqrt{ab}}+\\cfrac{2}{b+\\sqrt{ab}}}=\n4ab+\\cfrac{a^3+b^3}{a+b}-\\cfrac{\\cfrac{2\\sqrt{a}\\sqrt{b}(\\sqrt{a}+\\sqrt{b})}{\\sqrt{a}+\\sqrt{b}}}{\\cfrac{2}{\\sqrt{a}(\\sqrt{a}+\\sqrt{b})}+\\cfrac{2}{\\sqrt{b}(\\sqrt{a}+\\sqrt{b})}}=\n4ab+a^2-ab+b^2-\\cfrac{2\\sqrt{ab}}{\\cfrac{2(\\sqrt{a}+\\sqrt{b})}{\\sqrt{ab}(\\sqrt{a}+\\sqrt{b})}}=\na^2+3ab+b^2-\\cfrac{2\\sqrt{ab}}{\\cfrac{2}{\\sqrt{ab}}}=a^2+3ab+b^2-ab=(a+b)^2.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 51,
    "problem": "51.\\ \\cfrac{x^\\frac{1}{2}+1}{x^\\frac{3}{2}+x+x^\\frac{1}{2}}:\\cfrac{1}{x^2-x^\\frac{1}{2}},&\n",
    "solution": "51. $\\cfrac{x^\\frac{1}{2}+1}{x^\\frac{3}{2}+x+x^\\frac{1}{2}}:\\cfrac{1}{x^2-x^\\frac{1}{2}}=\n[a=x^\\frac{1}{2}]=\\cfrac{a+1}{a^3+a^2+a}:\\cfrac{1}{a^4-a}=\n\\cfrac{a+1}{a(a^2+a+1)}\\cdot a(a-1)(a^2+a+1)=a^2-1=x-1.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 52,
    "problem": "52.\\ \\cfrac{a^2+a^\\frac{1}{2}}{a^\\frac{1}{2}+1}\\cdot\\cfrac{a^\\frac{1}{2}-1}{a^\\frac{3}{2}-a+a^\\frac{1}{2}}.\n\\end{array}$\\\\\n",
    "solution": "52. $\\cfrac{a^2+a^\\frac{1}{2}}{a^\\frac{1}{2}+1}\\cdot\\cfrac{a^\\frac{1}{2}-1}{a^\\frac{3}{2}-a+a^\\frac{1}{2}}=\n[x=a^\\frac{1}{2}]=\\cfrac{x^4+x}{x+1}\\cdot\\cfrac{x-1}{x^3-x^2+x}\n=\\cfrac{x(x+1)(x^2-x+1)}{x+1}\\cdot\\cfrac{x-1}{x(x^2-x+1)}=\nx-1=\\sqrt{a}-1.$\\\\\n"
  },
  {
    "i": 53,
    "problem": "53. Вычислите $\\cfrac{2ab(a^3-b^3)}{a^2+ab+b^2}-\\cfrac{(a-b)(a^4-b^4)}{a^2-b^2},$ где $a=-1,\\underbrace{5\\ldots56}_{2024},\\ b=5,\\underbrace{4\\ldots44}_{2024}.$\n\\newpage\n",
    "solution": "53. $\\cfrac{2ab(a^3-b^3)}{a^2+ab+b^2}-\\cfrac{(a-b)(a^4-b^4)}{a^2-b^2}=\n\\cfrac{2ab(a-b)(a^2+ab+b^2)}{a^2+ab+b^2}-\\cfrac{(a-b)(a^2-b^2)(a^2+b^2)}{a^2-b^2}=\n2ab(a-b)-(a-b)(a^2+b^2)=(b-a)(a^2-2ab+b^2)=(b-a)^3=7^3=343.$\n\\newpage\n"
  }
]